Welcome.
欢迎。
Starting from this section, we're going to use some climb animation to swap out this
从这一节开始，我们将使用一些爬升动画来替换这个
default movement animation when we're climbing.
当我们在攀登时，默认的运动动画。
And to handle that, instead of directly modifying the existing animation blueprint, I like to
为了解决这个问题，我不是直接修改现有的动画蓝图，而是
do it from scratch using C++.
使用C++从头开始。
I think they'll be much clearer for us to know and understand what's going on under
我认为他们会让我们更清楚地知道和理解下面发生的事情
the hood.
引擎盖。
So I'm going to go inside of this C++ classes folder and inside of it, inside of public,
所以我将进入这个C++类文件夹，在它的内部，在公共的内部，
I'm going to create a new C++ class.
我将创建一个新的C++类。
And I'm going to select all classes and type in nminstance and select this nminstance.
然后我将选择所有类，然后输入nminstance，然后选择这个nminstance。
Click next.
单击下一步。
I'm going to rename this to character nminstance and place it under the folder named nminstance
我要将其重命名为Character nminstance，并将其放在名为nminstance的文件夹下
and click create class.
并单击创建类。
Alright, live coding succeeded, I'm going to close my project and click this reload
好了，实时编码成功，我要关闭我的项目并单击此重新加载
all.
全。
Then I'm going to go to the header file of my nminstance.
然后我将转到我的实例的头文件。
And you can see the parent class of it is this new nminstance.
您可以看到它的父类就是这个新实例。
I'm going to select it and press F12 to go inside of it.
我要选择它，然后按F12进入它的内部。
In order for everything to work properly, there are two functions that we need to override.
为了让一切正常工作，我们需要重写两个函数。
So I'm going to search for them.
所以我要去找他们。
The first one is this native initialize animation.
第一个是本机初始化动画。
So this is like the begin play for our animation blueprint.
这就像是我们动画蓝图的开始。
So I'm going to override this function, copy it and go back to my header file.
所以我要覆盖这个函数，复制它，然后返回到我的头文件。
I'm going to create a public section and place the function in here, mark it as override.
我将创建一个公共部分，并将该函数放在此处，将其标记为覆盖。
And the second function that we need to override is this native update animation.
我们需要覆盖的第二个功能是本机更新动画。
So I'm going to copy this.
所以我要复制这个。
This is like the take of our animation blueprint.
这就像我们的动画蓝图一样。
So I'm going to go back to my header file, paste it in here and mark this function as
因此，我将返回到我的头文件，将其粘贴到此处，并将此函数标记为
override.
超驰。
All right, I'm going to create two function definitions and create one for this update
好的，我将创建两个函数定义，并为此更新创建一个
animation.
动画。
So first thing I'm going to call super inside of these two functions.
所以我首先要在这两个函数中调用。
So first one is for this native initialize animation and the second one is for this update
第一个是本机初始化动画，第二个是这个更新
animation.
动画。
So copy this line, paste it in here, copy this one, paste it in here, delete this float.
复制这行，粘贴到这里，复制这行，粘贴到这里，删除这个浮动。
All right, this is the basic setup that we need to do.
好了，这是我们需要做的基本设置。
If you'd like to catch up with me, you can pause the video now and give this a go.
如果你想跟上我，你现在可以暂停视频，然后试一试。
Welcome back.
欢迎回来。
The next thing that we need to do in here, we need to create all of those variables needed
我们在这里需要做的下一件事是，我们需要创建所有需要的变量
for our animation.
为了我们的动画。
So go back to my header file.
因此，返回到我的头文件。
I'm going to create a private section.
我要创建一个私人区域。
So the first one is going to have an empty U property.
所以第一个函数将有一个空的U属性。
So this is going to be our character reference.
因此，这将是我们的角色参考。
So I'm going to go back to the header file and I'm going to copy this type.
所以我要回到头文件，我要复制这种类型。
So it's called a climbing system character.
所以它被称为攀登系统角色。
I'm going to copy this and paste it in here.
我要把这个复制并粘贴到这里。
And I'm going to name this pointer climbing system character.
我将给这个指针爬升系统角色命名。
And we do need to forward declare the type in here.
我们确实需要在这里转发声明类型。
So copy this one, create a forward declare.
所以复制这个，创建一个Forward声明。
All right, the second variable is going to have the same empty U property.
好的，第二个变量将具有相同的空U属性。
So this is going to be a reference of our custom movement component.
因此，这将是我们的自定义移动组件的参考。
So go back to the header file.
因此，回到头文件。
I'm going to copy this type.
我要复印这一种。
Go back to my header file.
返回到我的头文件。
I'm going to first forward declare it.
我要先把它宣布出来。
So place it in here.
所以把它放在这里。
Then scroll down, place this one in here.
然后向下滚动，把这个放在这里。
I'm going to call this variable custom movement component.
我将把这个变量称为自定义移动组件。
All right, first thing we need to assign these pointers some valid values.
好的，首先我们需要为这些指针分配一些有效的值。
So go back to my cpp file.
所以回到我的CPP文件。
Instead of this native initialize animation, I'm going to type climbing system character
我将不输入本机初始化动画，而是输入攀登系统角色
is going to equal to the result of a cast.
将等于一次铸型的结果。
So the type is going to be a climbing system character.
因此，类型将是一个攀登系统的角色。
And we're going to cast from this try get pong owner.
我们将从这次试镜中挑选出乒乓球老板。
And we do need to include the header file of our character and we can get that from
我们确实需要包括我们角色的头文件，我们可以从
our custom movement component.
我们的定制移动组件。
So go back to its cpp file.
因此，请返回到其CPP文件。
I'm going to copy this line and I'm going to paste it in here.
我要复制这行，然后粘贴到这里。
So after this line, I'm going to check if this pointer is valid.
在这一行之后，我要检查这个指针是否有效。
And I'm going to get hold of the custom movement component.
我将获得定制移动组件。
So access the getter that we created is called get custom movement component.
因此，访问我们创建的getter称为Get Custom Move Component。
And I'm going to store this in the variable that we created.
我将把它存储在我们创建的变量中。
So it's called custom movement component.
所以它被称为自定义移动组件。
In case I forget, I'm going to include the header file of our movement component as well.
如果我忘记了，我还将包括我们的移动组件的头文件。
So go back to its cpp file.
因此，请返回到其CPP文件。
I'm going to copy this and paste it in here.
我要把这个复制并粘贴到这里。
Alright I'm going to compile first to see if there are any errors.
好的，我要先编译一下，看看有没有错误。
I have a successful compile.
我有一个成功的汇编。
Once we get hold of the references we need inside of this native update animation, I'm
一旦我们掌握了这个本机更新动画中所需的引用，我就
going to first check if this climbing system character is valid.
我要先检查一下这个攀爬系统的角色是否有效。
So if it's not valid or this custom movement component is not valid, either way I'm going
因此，如果它无效或此自定义移动组件无效，无论哪种方式，我都会选择
to return out of this function.
从这个函数中返回。
Once we get past this if check, we should have a valid climbing system character and
一旦我们通过了这个IF检查，我们应该有一个有效的爬升系统特征和
a valid custom movement component.
有效的自定义移动组件。
And in here we should get all the variables we need for our animation.
在这里，我们应该得到动画所需的所有变量。
So go back to my header file.
因此，返回到我的头文件。
I'm going to start to create some variables.
我将开始创建一些变量。
So the first one is going to be a U property.
所以第一个将是U属性。
Since the content here is the same, I'm going to copy some of the U properties from our
因为这里的内容是相同的，所以我将从我们的
custom movement component.
自定义移动组件。
So scroll down to this BP variables.
所以向下滚动到这个BP变量。
I'm going to copy this one and go back to this nm instance, paste it in here.
我要复制这个，然后返回到这个nm实例，粘贴到这里。
I'm going to modify some of the content.
我要修改一些内容。
So instead of add the defaults only, I'm going to change this to visible anywhere.
因此，我将不再只添加默认设置，而是将其更改为在任何地方都可见。
And the category I'm going to change it to reference.
以及我要将其更改为引用的类别。
And this variable is going to be a float.
这个变量将是一个浮点数。
I'm going to call it ground speed.
我把它叫做地面速度。
And right below this variable I'm going to create a function to get.
在这个变量的正下方，我将创建一个要获取的函数。
So I'm going to call this one get ground speed.
所以我把这个叫做GET GROUND SPEED。
And I'm going to copy this U property.
我要复制这个U的财产。
We only need a few more of this.
我们只需要再来几个。
So the second variable I'm going to call this one is going to be a float.
所以我要叫它的第二个变量，会是一个浮点数。
And I'm going to call it air speed.
我把它叫做空速。
And I'm going to create a function for it.
我要为它创建一个函数。
I'm going to call it get air speed.
我要把它叫做“获得空速”。
And there are two more that we need.
我们还需要另外两个。
So copy this one again.
所以把这个再复制一遍。
So the next one is going to be a Boolean.
所以下一个将是一个布尔值。
I'm going to call this be shoot move and create a function for it.
我将把它命名为BE Shoot Move，并为它创建一个函数。
It's going to be void.
这将是无效的。
I'm going to call it get shoot move.
我要把它叫做Get Shoot Move。
And the last one create another U property.
而最后一个创建了另一个U属性。
So this one is going to be another Boolean.
所以这将是另一个布尔值。
I'm going to call this be is falling and create a function to get.
我将把它命名为Be is Fall，并创建一个要获取的函数。
So I'm going to call it get is falling.
所以我要把它命名为GET正在下降。
Alright I'm going to create a bunch of function definitions.
好的，我将创建一组函数定义。
Alright first thing I'm going to call these functions that I just created inside of this
好的，首先我要调用我刚刚在这个内部创建的这些函数
update animation.
更新动画。
So copy them and paste them inside of this function.
因此，将它们复制并粘贴到此函数中。
And I'm going to start to implement these functions.
我将开始实现这些功能。
So the first one ground speed.
所以第一个是地面速度。
That's something we can get from this climbing system character.
这就是我们可以从这个攀登系统角色中得到的东西。
So I'm going to access the function get velocity.
所以我要访问函数，获取速度。
And since we're only interested in the ground speed, we'll need to use a function from Kitsma
因为我们只对地面速度感兴趣，所以我们需要使用Kitsma的函数
math library.
数学库。
So I'm going to directly search for it in here.
所以我会直接在这里搜索它。
So it's called Kitsma math library.
所以它被称为Kitsma数学库。
And you can see this is its header file.
你可以看到这是它的头文件。
I'm going to go to its CPP file, copy the first line, close it and paste it in here.
我将转到它的cpp文件，复制第一行，关闭它，然后粘贴到这里。
So we'll need to access the function U Kitsma math library.
所以我们需要访问函数U Kitsma数学库。
And the function we need is called vsize xy.
我们需要的函数叫做vsizexy。
And I'm going to copy this one and paste it in here.
我要复制这个，然后把它粘贴到这里。
And delete this one, so this is our ground speed and I'm going to assign the value of
删除这个，这是我们的地面速度，我将赋值为
it to this ground speed.
它达到了这个地面速度。
Alright, for this error speed, same thing.
好的，对于这个错误速度，情况是一样的。
We are going to access this get velocity, but this time we're only interested in the
我们将访问此获取速度，但这一次我们只对
z component.
Z分量。
So this is our error speed.
这就是我们的错误速度。
I'm going to assign the value to the variable error speed.
我要把这个值赋给变量错误速度。
And for this function getShoeMove, there are a few if checks.
对于这个函数getShoeMove，有几个if检查。
So first thing I'm going to check, this custom movement component, I'm going to get hold
所以我要做的第一件事是检查这个定制的移动组件，我要拿到
of the function getCurrentAcceleration.
函数getCurrentAcceleration。
So if our acceleration.size is greater than zero and our ground speed is greater than
所以如果我们的加速度大于零，我们的地面速度大于
5.f and v is falling is false.
5.f和v正在下降是假的。
So if these three conditions are true, then we should move.
因此，如果这三个条件成立，那么我们应该采取行动。
So I'm going to assign their values to this beShoeMove.
所以我要把它们的值赋给这个beShoeMove。
And add the semicolon at the end.
并在末尾加上分号。
Alright, the last function getIsFalling, we can get that from our custom moving component
好的，最后一个函数getIsFling，我们可以从我们的定制移动组件中获得它
and access the function isFalling.
并访问正在倒下的功能。
And assign the value to this beIsFalling.
并将该值赋给此beIsFling。
Alright that's pretty much it.
好了，差不多就是这样了。
These are all the variables that we need to recreate the animation blueprint.
这些都是我们重建动画蓝图所需的变量。
Alright I'm going to compile first.
好的，我要先编译一下。
I have a successful compile.
我有一个成功的汇编。
I'm going to launch my editor back.
我要让我的编辑回来。
So going inside of my editor, I'm going to go to this ClimbSystem and right mouse button
因此，在我的编辑器中，我将转到这个气候系统，然后用鼠标右键
click.
单击。
Go to animation and create an animation blueprint.
转到动画并创建动画蓝图。
And the skeleton here, I'm going to select this SKMannequin and the pairing class.
这里的框架，我将选择这个SKMannequin和配对类。
I'm going to use this C++ class that we just created.
我将使用我们刚刚创建的这个C++类。
So you'll pick this character and instance and click create.
因此，您将拾取此角色和实例，然后单击创建。
I'm going to rename this animation blueprint to abp_climbsys_character and double click
我要将此动画蓝图重命名为ABP_appbsys_Character，然后双击
to open it.
才能打开它。
And if you go to this icon here, click it and show this inherited variables.
如果你在这里找到这个图标，点击它并显示这个继承的变量。
You can see these are the variables that we created inside of C++.
您可以看到这些是我们在C++中创建的变量。
Alright that's all we need to do for now.
好了，我们现在要做的就是这些。
So I'm going to go back to my content browser, open this ClimbingSystem character and I'm
所以我要回到我的内容浏览器，打开这个气候系统角色，我
going to swap out this animation blueprint.
换出这张动画蓝图。
So I'm going to change this to this abp_climbsys_character and click compile.
因此，我将把它更改为这个ABP_CONTIABSYS_CHARACTER，然后单击编译。
Now if I click play again, you can see we no longer have the animation and we are back
现在，如果我再次点击播放，你可以看到我们不再有动画，我们又回来了
to this default A pose.
设置为此默认的A姿势。
And in next lecture, we are going to use all the variables that we created to rebuild this
在下一节课中，我们将使用我们创建的所有变量来重建这个
animation blueprint.
动画蓝图。
So this is the key function inside of our C++ class and these are the first four variables
这是我们的C++类中的关键函数，这是前四个变量
that we need.
这是我们需要的。
Feel free to refer back to the video if you need help.
如果您需要帮助，请随时回顾视频。
Alright it's time for you to do the same and I'll see you in the next lecture.
好了，你们也该这么做了，我们下一节课再见。
Bye.
再见。